<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>StarAtt</title>
    <link>http://staratt.cc/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on StarAtt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 14:14:17 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://staratt.cc/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My music</title>
      <link>http://staratt.cc/en/lists/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 14:14:17 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://staratt.cc/en/lists/music/</guid>
      <description>Recent works are on my Peertube, which is hosted on Oracle Cloud. If Peertube doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for some reason, you can also visit my Soundcloud or Youtube profile。&#xA;Concert Band Garden Imbroglio Piano Poignant Rebirthday Others AH Modified and recorded AVS plugins in Winamp.&#xA;Sonic Pi &amp;amp; Improviz Live in Neovim First live recording after setting up Neovim configuration for Sonic Pi (v4) and Improviz on CachyOS.&#xA;Floating Debut Waltz Music Box </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to access Windows&#39; OneDrive folder from Linux</title>
      <link>http://staratt.cc/en/posts/access-windows-onedrive-from-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 11:20:51 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://staratt.cc/en/posts/access-windows-onedrive-from-linux/</guid>
      <description>My friend had some files in the OneDrive folder on Windows&amp;rsquo; partition, wondering how to access them directly from Linux (because of the unsupported reparse point error). Hence, this article was born.&#xA;Install ntfs-3g (with FUSE support so you can mount drives without sudo). Download the plugin from Web Archive. Extract the zip and place the plugin (ntfs-plugin-9000001a.so in linux-64 or other platforms) under /usr/lib/ntfs-3g/. You might need to create the folder yourself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distros to begin</title>
      <link>http://staratt.cc/en/lists/distros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 23:22:23 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://staratt.cc/en/lists/distros/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of Linux distributions to choose from. Here are some distros I like and recommand to start with:&#xA;Debian/Ubuntu Based Mint Zorin OS Arch Based CachyOS Why not Ubuntu? Since Ubuntu 22.04, it directs apt install to Snap by default, which is forced by Canonical and might lead to broken or unexpected packages. The default desktop layout (vertical teskbar and Activities) can also be somewhat confusing to newcomers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FOSS List</title>
      <link>http://staratt.cc/en/lists/foss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 22:35:38 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://staratt.cc/en/lists/foss/</guid>
      <description>Everything listed works on Windows, macOS and Linux.&#xA;Web Browser Floorp Brave General HackMD (online collaboration) LibreOffice (office suite) Marktext (Markdown editor) Syncthing (P2P synchronisation between devices) Xplorer (file explorer) ImageGlass (image viewer) VLC Media Player (media player) 7-Zip (file compressor and extractor) Communication Element Jitsi Meet Scorewriter MuseScore Frescobaldi (Lilypond) DAW Ardour Zrythm Graphic Krita Inkscape GIMP Darktable Blender Video Kdenlive PKMs AFFiNE Anytype Misc OBS Studio (screen recording, streaming) Rustdesk (remote desktop) Audacity (basic audio editing) Bitwarden (password manager) Nextcloud (NAS) </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://staratt.cc/en/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 10:16:17 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://staratt.cc/en/about/</guid>
      <description>Open Source advocate. Composer. Programmer. Pro-gamer. Likes Gamelan. Living somewhere around (24°N, 121°E) on earth.&#xA;Linux Tried various distros since 2018, including Ubuntu, elementary OS, Linux Mint, Zorin OS, Ubuntu Studio, AV Linux, Feren OS, KDE neon, Regata OS, MX Linux, Nitrux, Manjaro, Arch Linux, Archcraft, Garuda Linux, Void Linux and openSUSE Thumbleweed.&#xA;Now live on CachyOS. I also recommend Zorin OS.&#xA;Music Play the clarinet and the piano whilst mostly compose for concert band and piano.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
