<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lists on StarAtt</title>
    <link>http://staratt.cc/en/lists/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lists on StarAtt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 14:14:17 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://staratt.cc/en/lists/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My music</title>
      <link>http://staratt.cc/en/lists/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 14:14:17 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://staratt.cc/en/lists/music/</guid>
      <description>Recent works are on my Peertube, which is hosted on Oracle Cloud. If Peertube doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for some reason, you can also visit my Soundcloud or Youtube profile。&#xA;Concert Band Garden Imbroglio Piano Poignant Rebirthday Others Floating Debut Waltz Music Box </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distros to begin</title>
      <link>http://staratt.cc/en/lists/distros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 23:22:23 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://staratt.cc/en/lists/distros/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of Linux distributions to choose from. Here are some distros I like and recommand to start with:&#xA;Debian/Ubuntu Based Mint Zorin OS Arch Based CachyOS Why not Ubuntu? Since Ubuntu 22.04, it directs apt install to Snap by default, which is forced by Canonical and might lead to broken or unexpected packages. The default desktop layout (vertical teskbar and Activities) can also be somewhat confusing to newcomers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FOSS List</title>
      <link>http://staratt.cc/en/lists/foss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 22:35:38 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://staratt.cc/en/lists/foss/</guid>
      <description>Everything listed works on Windows, macOS and Linux.&#xA;Web Browser Floorp Brave General HackMD (online collaboration) LibreOffice (office suite) Marktext (Markdown editor) Syncthing (P2P synchronisation between devices) Xplorer (file explorer) ImageGlass (image viewer) VLC Media Player (media player) 7-Zip (file compressor and extractor) Communication Element Jitsi Meet Scorewriter MuseScore Frescobaldi (Lilypond) DAW Ardour Zrythm Graphic Krita Inkscape GIMP Darktable Blender Video Kdenlive PKMs AFFiNE Anytype Misc OBS Studio (screen recording, streaming) Rustdesk (remote desktop) Audacity (basic audio editing) Bitwarden (password manager) Nextcloud (NAS) </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
